Gregory Pincus Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Professional Correspondence, 1942-1967 (Box 8-134)
  - General File, 1938-1967 (Box 8-104)
    - 1963
      - Public Health Service National Institutes of Health, (2 folders)
      - Puerto Rico
        - General, (2 folders)
        - Paniagua, Manuel (Box 66)
        - Pendleton, Satterwaite A.
      - Putney School
      - "Q-R" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
      - "S" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
      - Schmid, Julius
      - Smith Kline & French (Box 67)
      - Societies miscellaneous
      - E. R. Squib & Sons
      - Squib Institute
      - Steroid training program, Clark University, Mass.
      - "T-U" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
      - University of British Colombia
      - "V" miscellaneous
      - Vismana Terapeuteci
      - "W" miscellaneous (Box 68)
      - Werthesson, Nicholas
      - Worcester Foundation for Experimental Biology
        - Expansion, (3 folders)
        - Interoffice Memoranda
        - Library committee
        - Public relations
        - Requisitions
        - Senior scientists meetings
        - Staff manuscripts
        - State Hospital
        - Trustees
      - World Academy of Arts and Sciences
      - "Y-Z" miscellaneous
    - 1964 (Box 69)
      - "A" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
      - Academic Press
      - American Cancer Society
      - American College of Obstetrics and Gynecology
      - American Physiological Society
      - Australian Symposium on Recent Advances: Quarian and Synthetic Steroids
      - Ayerst Laboratories
      - "B" miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box 70)
      - Books and reprints
      - Boston University
      - Bush Group, Worcester Foundation for Experimental Biology
      - Ciba Foundation (Box 71)
      - City of Hope Dinner
      - "D-F" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
      - Fan mail
      - Food and Drug Administration
      - "G" miscellaneous
      - Gerontological Society
      - "H" miscellaneous, (6 folders) (Box 72)
      - Haiti, (2 folders)
      - Hertz, Roy
      - "I" miscellaneous
      - International Congress on Endocrinology, second congress
      - International Congress on Endocrinology Hormonal Steroids, second congress, 1962-1964, (3 folders)
      - International Union Against Cancer (Box 73)
      - "J" miscellaneous
      - Jaques, Jean
        - Compounds
        - Correspondence, 1958-1964, (2 folders)
      - "K-L" miscellaneous, (6 folders) (Box 74)
      - Lasker Foundation
      - Lasker, Mary
      - Laurention Hormone Conference
      - Lederle Laboratory seminar
      - "M" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
      - Medical Research Institute of Worcester
      - Mercke, Sharp & Dohme
      - Mexican Endocrine Society
      - "N" miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box 75)
      - National Institute of Radio Logical Sciences, 1962
      - National Science Foundation, (2 folders)
      - "O-P" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
      - Physiology of Reproduction training program, (2 folders) (Box 76)
      - Pincus
        - Itineraries
        - Travel expense vouchers
      - Planned Parenthood Federation of America
      - International Planned Parenthood Federation, (2 folders)
      - Population Council (Box 77)
      - Puerto Rico
        - Anti-cancer project, (2 folders)
        - Miscellany, (8 folders)
      - "R" miscellaneous, (3 folders) (Box 78)
      - Requisitions
      - "S" miscellaneous, (9 folders)
      - Julius Schmidt, Inc. (Box 79)
      - Squibb Institute
      - Steroid training program biochemistry, Worcester Foundation for Experimental Biology
      - "T-U" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
      - United States Public Health Service, National Institutes of Health, (2 folders)
      - University of Chile
      - University of Miami
      - University of Utah
      - "V" miscellaneous
      - Vismara Terapeutici
      - Vister research (Box 80)
        - Bank account
        - Data reports
        - Reports
      - "W" miscellaneous, (6 folders)
      - Worcester Foundation for Experimental Biology
        - Directors
        - Enguall
        - Executive committee
        - Expansion of research
        - Financial
        - Library
        - Miscellaneous committees, (4 folders) (Box 81)
        - Public relations
        - Senior scientists
        - Trustees
      - Urraws, Henry
      - World Academy of Arts and Sciences
      - "Z" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - 1965 (Box 82)
      - "A" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
      - Academic Press
      - "B" miscellaneous, (7 folders)
      - Banik, Upendra K.
      - Books and reprints (Box 83)
      - Boston University
      - "C" miscellaneous, (6 folders)
      - Ciba Foundation
      - Ciba Pharmaceutical
      - Coirre (Laboratoires) (Box 84)
      - "D-E" miscellaneous, (5 folders)
      - Endocrine Society
      - "F" miscellaneous
      - Fan mail
      - "G" miscellaneous, (3 folders) (Box 85)
      - "Geriatric Focus"
      - "H" miscellaneous, (6 folders)
      - Haiti
        - Laraque, Felix
        - Miscellaneous correspondence
      - "I" miscellaneous
      - Institute of Gerontology Bulletin (Box 86)
      - "J-L" miscellaneous, (7 folders)
      - Lasker, Foundation
      - Lasker, Mary
      - Laurentian Hormone Conference
      - "M" miscellaneous, (6 folders)
      - Meade Johnson Co.
      - Medical Research Institute of Worcester
      - "N" miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box 87)
      - National Academy of Sciences
        - Correspondence
        - Printed Matter
      - National Science Foundation
        - General
        - Japanese-American Seminar on Dynamics of Steroid Hormones, (6 folders) (Box 88)
      - Norwich Pharmacal Co.
      - "O" miscellaneous
      - "P" miscellaneous, (3 folders) (Box 89)
      - Pan-American Congress of Endocrinology, (6 folders)
      - Physiology of reproduction
      - Pincus. itineraries (Box 90)
      - Planned Parenthood Federation of America International Planned Parenthood Federation, (2 folders)
      - Population Council
      - Puerto Rico
        - Correspondence, (3 folders)
        - Paniagua, Satterthwaite, (2 folders) (Box 91)
      - "R" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
      - Requisitions, Worcester Foundation for Experimental Biology
      - "S" miscellaneous, (9 folders)
      - Julius Schmid, Inc. (Box 92)
      - Smith, Kline & French
      - Steroid training program
      - "T-U" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
      - United States Public Health Service
        - Cancer chemotherapy
        - Correspondence
        - National Institute of Child Health & Human Development
      - "V" miscellaneous
      - Vismara Terapeutici
      - "W" miscellaneous, (6 folders) (Box 93)
      - World Health Organization, Scientific Group on Mechanism of Action of Sex Hormones and Analagous Substances
        - Correspondence
        - Miscellaneous
      - "Y-Z" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - 1966 (Box 94)
      - "A" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
      - Academic Press
      - American Association of Anatomists
      - American Cancer Society
      - Association Lationamerica de Iinvestigaciones en Reproduccion Humana
      - "B" miscellaneous, (8 folders)
      - Barren Foundation
      - Books and reprints ordered
      - Boston University
      - "C" miscellaneous, (4 folders) (Box 95)
      - Canadian Broadcasting Corp.
      - Chinnatamby, Siva
      - Ciba Foundation
      - Courrier colloquium
      - "D" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
      - Dorfman, Ralph
      - "E" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
      - Escher, Dr. George
      - "F" miscellaneous
      - Fan mail
      - Ford Foundation Conference on Physiology of Reproduction
      - "G-H" miscellaneous, (9 folders) (Box 96)
      - Haiti
      - "I" miscellaneous
      - International Congress on Hormonal Steroids, second congress
        - Correspondence, (3 folders) (Box 97)
        - Financial
        - Miscellaneous, (2 folders)
        - Program, (2 folders)
      - "J-L" miscellaneous, (7 folders) (Box 98)
      - Lasker Foundation
      - Lasker, Mary
      - Laurentian Hormone Conference
      - "M-N" miscellaneous, (8 folders)
      - National Academy of Sciences
        - Annual meeting
        - Correspondence (Box 99)
        - Symposium
      - National Science Foundation, (2 folders)
      - Norwich Pharmacal Co.
      - "O-P" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
      - Physiology of Reproduction, training program (Box 100)
      - Pincus
        - Itineraries
        - Travel vouchers
      - Pituitary Studies
      - Planned Parenthood Federation of America International Planned Parenthood Federation, (3 folders)
      - Puerto Rico, (2 folders) (Box 101)
      - "Q-S" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
      - Steroid training program
      - "T" miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box 102)
      - Taiwan project
      - "U" miscellaneous
      - United States Public Health Service
        - Cancer chemotherapy
        - Committee on General and Comparative Endocrinology
        - Miscellaneous correspondence
      - "V" miscellaneous
      - Vismara Terapeutici
      - "W" miscellaneous, (6 folders)
      - Worcester Foundation for Experimental Biology
      - World Health organization
      - "Y-Z" miscellaneous
    - 1967 (Box 103)
      - "A-C" miscellaneous
      - Academic Press
      - American Medical Association Awards Dinner
      - Australian & New Zealand Association for Advancement of Science
      - Ciba Foundation
      - "E-G" miscellaneous
      - Fan mail
      - Gordon Research Conference
      - "H-K" miscellaneous
      - Harvard Medical Society
      - Harvey lecture, Albert Einstein College
      - International Congress of Endoctrinology, third congress
      - "L-P" miscellaneous, (5 folders)
      - Pincus (Box 104)
        - Expense vouchers
        - Russia trip, (2 folders)
      - Planned Parenthood Federation of America
      - International Planned Parenthood Federation, (2 folders)
      - Puerto Rico, (2 folders)
      - "Q-R" miscellaneous
      - "S-U" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
      - United States Public Health Service
      - University of Pennsylvania
      - Worcester Foundation for Experimental Biology, symposium
      - "W-Z" miscellaneous
  - G. D. Searle & Company File, 1942-1967 (Box 105-115)
    Letters received and copies of letters sent, including related material concerning the G. D. Searle & Co. and Pincus's relation to it.
    Arranged chronologically by year.
    - 1942-1944, correspondence (Box 105)
    - 1944-1945, research conference
    - 1945-1946, correspondence
    - 1944-1948, miscellaneous
    - 1949-1950
    - 1950-1951, Bergstrom, C.
    - 1951
      - Incoming
      - Miscellany
      - Outgoing
    - 1952 (Box 106)
      - Incoming
      - Outgoing
    - 1953
      - Assay reports
      - Compounds
      - Incoming
      - Outgoing
    - 1954
      - Assay report
      - Compound requests
      - Compound tests (Box 107)
      - Incoming
      - Outgoing
      - Patent applications
    - 1955
      - Assay reports, (2 folders)
      - Correspondence
      - Compound requests
        - General
        - Raymond, Albert L.
      - Patent applications, (2 folders)
    - 1956 (Box 108)
      - Assay reports
      - Compound requests
      - Compound tests
      - Correspondence, (2 folders)
    - 1957
      - Abstracts
      - Assay reports
      - Compound requests
      - Correspondence (Box 109)
        - General
        - Raymond, Albert L.
      - Packing slips
    - 1958
      - Assay reports
      - Compound requests
      - Correspondence (Box 110)
        - General, (6 folders)
        - Raymond, Albert L.
    - 1959
      - Assay reports
      - Compound requests
      - Correspondence (Box 111)
        - General, (3 folders)
        - Raymond, Albert L.
    - 1960
      - Assay reports
      - Correspondence
        - General, (4 folders)
        - Raymond, Albert L. (Box 112)
    - 1961
      - Assay reports
      - Compound requests
      - Correspondence
        - General, (4 folders)
        - Raymond Albert L.
    - 1962 (Box 113)
      - Assay reports
      - Correspondence
        - General, (4 folders)
        - Raymond, Albert L.
    - 1963 (Box 114)
      - Assay reports
      - Compound requests
      - Correspondence
        - General, (5 folders)
        - Raymond, Albert L.
      - Miscellaneous
    - 1964 (Box 115)
      - Compound requests
      - Correspondence
        - General, (5 folders)
        - Raymond, Albert L.
      - Miscellaneous
    - 1965
      - Compound requests
      - Correspondence
      - Miscellaneous
  - Cancer Chemotherapy National Service Center File, 1956-1960 (Box 116-120)
    Correspondence, minutes of meetings, reports, memoranda, and related material concerning Pincus's work with the center.
    Arranged by type of material and chronologically thereunder.
    - Minutes of commissions and panels (Box 116)
      - 1956-1957, (2 folders)
      - 1958 - 1959, May, (6 folders) (Box 117)
      - 1959, June-Dec.-1960, (3 folders) (Box 118)
    - Clinical studies, 1956-1960, (11 folders) (Box 119)
    - Correspondence, 1956-1960, (3 folders) (Box 120)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Compounds for clinical tests
      - Endicott, Kenneth M.
      - Progesterone assay
      - Segaloff,Albert
      - Sessoms, Stuart
      - Steroid compounds
      - Vollmer, Eurwin P.
  - Grants File, 1944-1966 (Box 121-134)
    Correspondence, memoranda, reports, and data concerning grants received by Pincus and his staff.
    Arranged by grant and alphabetically by title of research project.
    - Aid for cancer research, 1953 (Box 121)
    - Air Force, 1954-1962
    - Holloman Air Force base
      - Elmadjian, Fred, final report
      - Influence of Hormones on Intimal Hyperplasia 1959-1962
      - Pincus-Elmadjian 1962
      - Pincus-Hoagland, Hudson, 1954-1955
    - American Cancer Society (Box 122)
      - Correspondence, 1945-1958, (4 folders)
      - Estrogen biosynthesis
      - Estrogen conference
      - Grant applications, (2 folders)
      - Legacy funds
      - Spectrophotometer purchase
      - Sterol biogenesis in relation to cancer, (2 folders)
    - Armour laboratories, 1952-1958, (3 folders) (Box 123)
    - Army contracts, 1952-1956
    - Astra Pharmaceutical Co., 1959-1961
    - Atomic Energy Commission, 1952-1961, (3 folders)
    - Ayerst, McKenna & Harrison, 1947-1958
    - Chemical Specialties Co., 1951-1955, (3folders)
    - Childs, Jane Coffin Memorial Fund, grant applications,1954-1964, (3 folders)
    - Ciba Pharmaceutical Products, 1950-1962, (2 folders) (Box 124)
    - Damon Runyan, 1953
    - Dazian Foundation, 1956-1957
    - Doris Duke Foundation, 1961-1963
    - Durham Foundation, 1957-1964
    - Eberhard-Stephens Laboratories, 1962
    - Henry and Lucy Moses Fund
    - L. Farber Co. 1949-1950
    - Life Insurance Medical Research Foundation, 1962-1963
    - Josiah Macy, Jr., Foundation, 1955-1961
    - Massachusetts Heart Association, 1959-1962
    - Merck & Co. 1950-1956, (3 folders)
    - Merck, Sharp, & Dohme 1950-1962, (2 folders) (Box 125)
    - Miscellaneous grants, 1944-1948, (2 folders)
    - National Research Council, 1945-1948
    - National Science Foundation
      - Biosynthesis of cholesterol
      - Building and instruments
      - Grant applications
    - Navy, 1952
    - New York Foundation, 1960-1962
    - Jessie Smith Noyes Foundation, 1963-1966
    - Organon, Inc. 1953-1961
    - Pacific Labs 1953
    - Parke Davis & Co., 1953-1958, (2 folders)
    - Charles Pfiszer & Co., 1954-1955 (Box 126)
    - Planned Parenthood Federation of America, 1957-1960, (2 folders)
    - Population Council 1958-1964
    - Ann Putnam Reed Memorial Building, 1962-1966, (2 folders)
    - Schering Corp., 1948-1962
    - Julius Schmid, Inc, 1958-1964, (3 folders)
    - Smith, Kline and French Laboratories, 1962 (Box 127)
    - E. R. Squibb & Sons 1962
    - Sterling Winthrop Research Institute, 1951-1953
    - United States Public Health Service
      - Action of nucleic acids, 1958-1966, (4 folders)
      - Anterior pituitary hormones, 1954-1961 (Box 128)
      - Applications
        - Bush Group, 1962-1964
        - Pending, 1963-1965
        - Rejected, 1962-1963
      - Assay methods, 1958-1961
      - Biological activities of steroids
        - 1954-1962
        - 1963-1965, (2 folders) (Box 129)
      - Cancer, 1947-1951, (3 folders)
      - Cancer chemotherapy, 1957-1964, (3 folders)
      - Clinical psychology graduation training, 1957-1958
      - Endocrinology research center, 1960-1961
      - Endocrinology panel, 1957-1961
      - Endocrinology study section, 1955-1956
      - Heart training, 1960
      - Hydrocortisone, 1957-1959
      - Miscellaneous staff grants, 1960-1964, (5 folders) (Box 130)
      - National Institute of Mental Health, 1950-1953
      - Old age, 1947-1952, (4 folders) (Box 131)
      - Pituitary hormones, 1957-1959
      - Radioactive steroids, 1960
      - Reproduction course, 1960-1961
      - Research career awards, 1962-1964
        - Pending
        - Rejected
      - Sex hormones and breast cancer, 1964
      - Steroid hormones and cancer, 1961-1962
      - Steroid hormones and cardiovascular functio, 1966 (Box 132)
      - Steroid metabolism, 1951-1962, (3 folders)
      - Steroid metabolism role of isolated organs, 1956-1969
      - Steroid metabolism and aging, 1956-1964
      - Stress, 1947-1950, (2 folders)
      - Tumor cells, 1964-1966 (Box 133)
      - Tumor growth, 1960-1961
    - Upjohn Co., 1947-1962
    - Vineland Poultry Laboratories
      - 1950-1953, (5 folders)
      - 1960-1960, (3 folders) (Box 134)
      - Patent applications, 1957-1958
      - Patents, 1962, (2 folders)
      - Research data, 1954-1955, (2 folders)
    - Vismara Terepeutici, 1962
    - Wilson Laboratories, 1950
- Speech, Article, and Book File, 1926-1967 (Box 135-146)
  Correspondence, manuscript and typescript drafts, notes, and other data concerning writings, speeches, and lectures by Pincus.
  Arranged chronologically by year and alphabetically therein by title.
  - 1926-1931, Genetics and social values (Box 135)
  - circa 1930, "17 Retasteroids of Plasma, Sweat and Uurine," with Hecter, O.
  - 1930, "Tissue Cultures at High Temperatures"
  - 1936, "Eggs of Mammals"
  - ca 1936, Sterility in Rabbits Produced by Injections of Oestrone and Related Compositions," with Kirsch, R.
  - circa 1937, "An Unfertilized Human Tubal Ovum," with Saunders, B.
  - 1937, "Total Urinary Estrogen," with Smith. G., and Smith, O. W., Developmental Physiology of Mammalian Eggs
  - 1940, "The Comparative Behavior of Mammalian Eggs in vivo and in vitro, VII," with Shapiro, H.
  - 1942-circa 1945, stress and related topics
  - circa 1944-1945," Stress," with Freeman, W.
  - 1949, "Adrenal Cortex Function in Stress"
  - 1951, Gerontology Congress and Journal of Gerontology slides (Box 136)
  - 1952, National Cancer Congress, slides, (2 folders)
  - 1953, Hormones vol. 3
  - 1954, "The Pysiology of Ovarian and Testis Hormones," for Hormones
  - 1955," Hormones and the Aging Process," G. D. Searle & Co. Conference
  - 1956
    - Aibs History of Worcester Foundation for Experimental Biology
    - "Hormonal Requirement of Implantation in the Rabbit," with Hafez
  - 1957
    - "Bioassay of Progesterone"
    - "Effects of Certain 19-Nor Steroids on the Menstrual Cycle, with Garcia, Celso-Ramon, and Rock, John
    - "The Effects of Certain 19-Nor Steroids upon Reproductive Processes," with Garcia, Celso-Ramon, and, John
    - "Effects of Estrogens and Steroids on Sex Differentiation in the Fowl"
    - "Fertility Control with Oral Medication," with Garcia, Celso-Ramon, Paniagua, Rice-Wray, Edris, Rock, John, nd Rodriguez
    - "Longterm Administration of Vilane to Human Subjects," G. D. Searle & Co. Conference (Box 137)
    - "Recent Developments in the Physiology and Pathophysiology of Adrenocortical Hormones"
    - "Hormones and Aging"
    - Rice-Wray report
  - 1958
    - "Aldosterome Excretion in Anxiety States"
      - "Anti-Progestational Activity of Estrogens in the Rabbit Endometrium," with Miyake
    - "Fertility Control with Oral Medication," Oliver Bird Lecture
    - "Hormonal Control of Ovulation and Early Development"
    - "Hormanal Influences on the Carbonic anhydrase Concentration in the Accessory Reproductive Tracts of the Rat," with Miyake, includes lantern slides
    - "Progestational Activity of Certain 19-Nor Steroids and Progesterone Derivatives," with Miyake
    - "Recent Developments in the Study of Adrenal Cortical Steroid
      - Biogenesis," Vienna Congress
    - "Studies on Fertility Control with Oral Steroid Medication," with Paniagua
    - "The Urinary Excretion"
  - 1959
    - "Biology of Fertility Control," Washington Post
    - "Clinical Effects of New Progestational Compounds"
    - "Effects of Certain 19-nor Steroids on Reproductive Processes and Fertility," with Chang, Garcia, Celso-Ramon, and John; Hoagland Symposium (Box 138)
    - "Field Trials with Norethynodrel as an Oral Contraceptive;" International Planned Parenthood Federation
      - International Conference, sixth conference
    - "In Vitro Cultivation of Mammalian Eggs," with Purshottam
    - "Ovulation in Mice," with Mason and Purshottam
    - "Progestational Agents and the Control of Fertility Vitamins and Hormones"
    - "Steroid Hormones and Aging in Man," American Association for the Advancement of Science symposium on aging studies with an oral contraceptive, with Borno, Garcia, Celso-Ramon, Laraque, Nicolas, Paniagua, Pendleton, and Rock, John
  - 1960 (Box 139)
    - "Control of Fertility"
    - "Further Studies on Progestin Bioassay Using the Eendometrial Lantern Slides"
    - "Metabolism and Mode of Action of Andrenocortical Hormones," Glasgow Conference
    - "Micro-Determination of Carbonic Anhydrase Activity in Animal Tissue," with Ogawa
    - "Parabiosis," by Miyake
    - "Prepration and Properties of the Cofactor of an ACTH-Inactivating Enzyme System from Human Blood," with Hopkins, Terner
    - "Progesteronegenesis in Ovarian Tissues," with Tamoki, B.
    - "Role of Steroids in the Control of Mammalian Ovulation," Harvard Conference On Ovulation Steroid Hormones and Aging in Man, (2 folders)
  - 1961 (Box 140)
    - "Steroids and Tumors" Canadian Cancer Conference, (2 folders)
    - "Suppression of Ovulation with Reference to Oral Contraceptives," Copenhagen Congress
    - "Annual Review of Physiology"
    - "Ant-Progestins," with Merrill, Ann P.
    - "Effects of Estrogen and Progestin on the Uterine Carbonic Anhydrase of Immature Rats"
    - "Estrogen Effects on the Carbonic Anhydrase Content of Mouse Uteri," with Ogawa, Y.
    - "Human Beings and the Human Race"
    - Miscellaneous manuscripts
    - "Ovulation Inhibition and Fertility Control"
    - "Sex Modifications Occurring in Fertile Hens Eggs." with Erickson, A.
  - 1962
    - "Anti-Ovulatory Effects of Reserpine When Administered to Immature Rats," with Hopkins, Thomas F.
    - "Carbonic Anhydrase in Steroid-Responsive Tissues," with Bialy, G.
    - "The Control of Human Reproduction"
    - "The Control of Ovulation and of Ovum Development"
    - "Disappearance of Fluorescent La-Belled Gonadotrophin from the Blood of the Rabbit," with Kulangara, A. C. (Box 141)
    - "Effect of Steroidal Anti-Progestins on the Implantations of Fertilized Eggs of Rats and Mice," with Banik, U. K.
    - "Hormonal Inhibition of Ovulation," with Garcia, Celson-Ramon
    - "Ladies Home Journal," 1962-1963
    - Review of"Mammalian Egg," Quarterly Review of Biology
    - Miscellaneous manuscripts
    - "A New, Highly Potent Oral Ovulation Inhibition"
    - "Progesterone Assay in the Rabbit by the Local Intrauterine
      - Response," with Kuragochi, Yutaka
  - 1963
    - "Anti-Progestine and Implantation. " with Banik, U. K., International Planned Parenthood Federatoipm, seventh conference
    - "Carbonice anhydrase"